# Inhyeok Choi

CV updated Aug. 2024

Department of Mathematics, Cornell University 583 Malott Hall, Ithaca, NY 14853, USA

Email: inhyeokchoi48@gmail.com

Website: https://inhyeokchoi48.github.io

# Research Interests

My research lies in the intersection of geometric topology, geometric group theory and probability theory. Research keywords include Teichmüller space, mapping class groups, Outer space,  $Out(F_N)$ , Gromov hyperbolic spaces, CAT(0) spaces, random walks, and dynamics of groups acting on spaces.

#### Positions

| 07/2024-          | Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, United States                                  |
|-------------------|--|
|                   | Harry Kesten Assistant Professor (Post-doc)                                    |
| 03/2023 – 06/2024 | Korea Institute for Advanced Study, Seoul, South Korea                         |
|                   | Project research fellow (-07/2023), June E Huh Fellow (08/2023-) (Post-doc)    |
|                   | Mentor: Prof. Sang-hyun Kim  |
| 03/2024 – 06/2024 | Fields Institute, Toronto, ON, Canada  |
|                   | Marsden Postdoctoral Fellowship (visiting for the program "Thematic program on |
|                   | Randomness and Geometry")  |
|                   | Mentor: Prof. Giulio Tiozzo  |

# Education

| 09/2018-02/2023 | Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea M.S. & Ph.D. Integrated Program in Mathematical Sciences |
|-----------------|---|
| 03/2015-08/2018 | Advisor: Prof. Hyungryul Baik  Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea                           |
| 33/2323 33/2323 | B.Sc. in Physics, Mathematical Sciences, and Biological Sciences<br>Summa Cum Laude   |

# Other Educational Experiences

| 12/2018-02/2019 | Exchange student, Tokyo Institute of Technology            |
|-----------------|--|
| 08/2017-02/2018 | Exchange student, École Polytechnique Féderale de Lausanne |
| 12/2015-06/2017 | Undergraduate researcher, Biomedical Optics Lab, KAIST     |
|                 | Advisor: Prof. YongKeun Park                               |
| 06/2015-08/2015 | Exchange student, University of California, Berkeley       |

# Awards and Honors

| 02/2023           | Best Thesis Award, 2023, Dept. of Mathematical Sciences, KAIST             |
|-------------------|--|
| 08/2022           | Best TA Award, 2022 Spring semester, Dept. of Mathematical Sciences, KAIST |
| 03/2017           | Dean's list, 2016 Fall semester, College of Natural Sciences, KAIST        |
| 12/2016           | Silver Prize, Korean Undergraduate Mathematics Competition (전국             |
|                   | 대학생수학경시대회), Korean Mathematical Society                                    |
| 03/2015 – 08/2018 | Korea Presidential Science Scholarship (대통령과학장학생), Korea Student Aid       |
|                   | Foundation   |
| 03/2015 – 08/2018 | KAIST Presidential Fellowship  |

# Publications & Preprints

- 1. Counting pseudo-Anosovs as weakly contracting isometries Preprint (2024). arXiv:2408.00603.
- 2. Confined subgroups in groups with contracting elements With *Ilya Gekhtman, Wenyuan Yang and Tianyi Zheng.* Preprint (2024). arXiv:2405.09070.
- 3. Contracting isometries and differentiability of the escape rate Preprint (2024). arXiv:2403.09992.
- 4. Random walks on groups and superlinear divergent geodesics With *Kunal Chawla, Vivian He and Kasra Rafi.* Preprint (2023), to appear in **Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems**. arXiv:2310.18506.
- Genericity of contracting geodesics in groups With Kunal Chawla and Giulio Tiozzo. Preprint (2023). arXiv:2308.01877.
- 6. Random walks and contracting elements III: Outer space and outer automorphism group Preprint (2023). arXiv:2212.12122.
- 7. Random walks and contracting elements II: Translation lengths and quasi-isometric embedding Preprint (2023), to appear in **Groups, Geometry, and Dynamics**. arXiv:2212.12119.
- 8. Random walks and contracting elements I: Deviation inequality and limit laws Preprint (2023). arXiv:2207.06597.
- 9. Random walks on mapping class groups (survey paper)
  With Hyungryul Baik.

EMS Surveys in Mathematical Sciences, 9 (2022), no. 2, pp. 279-320. https://doi.org/10.4171/EMSS/59.

- Pseudo-Anosovs are exponentially generic in mapping class groups
   Geometry & Topology, Volume 28, pp. 1923-1955. (2024) https://doi.org/10.2140/gt.2024.28.
   1923.
- 11. Central limit theorem and geodesic tracking on hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces

  Advances in Mathematics, Volume 431, 109236 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aim.2023.

  109236.
- 12. Linear growth of translation lengths of random isometries on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces

With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.

Journal of the Institute of Mathematics of Jussieu, published online 2023:1-45. https://doi:10.1017/S1474748023000373.

- 13. Simple length spectra as moduli for hyperbolic surfaces and rigidity of length identities With *Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.*Preprint (2020). arXiv:2012.05652.
- 14. On the surjectivity of the Symplectic representation of the mapping class group With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.

**Topology and its Applications**, Volume 322, 108334 (2022). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.topol. 2022.108334.

- 15. Topological entropy of pseudo-Anosov maps from a typical Thurston construction With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.
  - International Mathematics Research Notices, Volume 2022, No. 24, pp. 19762-19904. (2022) https://doi.org/10.1093/imrn/rnab167
- 16. Inhyeok Choi, KyeoReh Lee, and YongKeun Park. Compensation of aberration and speckle noise in quantitative phase imaging using lateral shifting and spiral phase integration. **Optics Express**, 25(24) pp. 30771-30779 (2017).

## Research Talks

#### Lecture series

- 2023.07.29. Growth of (sub)groups with hyperbolicity. (3 lectures and 1-week group discussion) Geometry in Groups 2024. TIFR-ICTS, Bangalore, India.
- 2024.05.03. Hyperbolicity of geodesics, counting and random walks. (4 lectures) Riverside Workshop on Geometric Group Theory 2024, UC Riverside.

#### Invited Talks

- 2024.10.22. Genericity of pseudo-Anosovs and quasi-isometries. CUNY Geometry & Topology Seminar, CUNY. (Tentative)
- 2024.09.24. Genericity of pseudo-Anosovs and quasi-isometries. KIAS-Rice Workshop on Geometric Topology, KIAS HCMC. (Tentative)
- 2024.09.05. Genericity of pseudo-Anosovs and quasi-isometries. *Cornell Dynamics Seminar*. (Tentative)
- 2024.05.13. Continuity of escape rate of random walks on CAT(0) spaces. Dynamics of group actions and random walks on groups, Fields Institute.
- 2024.04.08. Genericity of pseudo-Anosov mapping classes. Young Geometric Group Theory XII, Bristol, UK.
- 2024.04.04. Genericity of pseudo-Anosovs (and fully irreducibles).  $Princeton\ Topology\ Seminar,$   $Princeton\ University.$
- 2024.04.02. Genericity of pseudo-Anosov mapping classes.  $Brandeis\ Topology\ Seminar,\ Brandeis\ University.$
- 2024.03.20. Random walks, superlinear divergence and quasi-isometry. *UBC Probability Seminar, University of British Columbia*.
- 2024.03.15. Growth of normal subgroups of a hyperbolic group. GT GAPS Seminar. (Online)
- 2024.02.29. Normal subgroups, confined subgroups and growth. Korea-France Workshop on Dynamical Group Theory, KIAS.
- 2024.01.17. Regularity of the escape rate and the asymptotic entropy of a random walk. KAIST GT Fair 2024, Busan, Korea.
- 2023.11.03. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. SNU Rookies Workshop 2023, Yangpeong, Korea.
- 2023.10.28. Generic mapping classes are pseudo-Anosov. 2023 KMS Fall Meeting, SNU.
- 2023.10.05. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. Tokyo-Seoul Conference in Mathematics 2023, The University of Tokyo.
- 2023.09.11. Random walks on groups without an action on hyperbolic spaces. Topology seminar, KAIST.
- 2023.09.04. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. World of Group Craft III. (Online)
- 2023.08.21. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. The 4th Korea-France Conference in Mathematics, KIAS.
- 2023.07.14. Geometry and dynamics of a finitely generated group. Workshop on Quantum Analysis 2023, Sokcho, Korea.

- 2023.04.20. Random walks on non-positively curved spaces: rate of escape, CLT and large deviation principle. *Conference on Probability and PDE, KAIST.*
- 2023.04.06. Counting pseudo-Anosov mapping classes. (series of 4 talks) Virtual Seminar on Geometry and Topology, KIAS.
- 2023.02.09. Asymmetry of a generic outer automorphism of a free group. The 18th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2022.11.08. Random subgroup is quasi-isometrically embedded.  $Geometry\ and\ Topology\ Seminar,\ CUNY.$
- 2022.11.08. The log-regularity of the hitting measure on the Gromov boundary. *Group actions, Geometry and Dynamics Seminar, Yale University.*
- 2022.11.02. Asymmetry of a typical outer automorphism. Geometry and Topology Seminar, Temple university.
- 2022.10.27. Simple length spectrum of a hyperbolic surface. Hyperbolic lunch, University of Toronto.
- 2022.10.24. Mapping class group, Teichmüller space and Bers' proof of Nielsen-Thurston's classification. *Dynamics Seminar, University of Toronto*.
- 2022.05.12. Typical behavior of random mapping classes and outer automorphisms. *Fudan Topology Seminar*. (Online)
- 2022.04.11. Limit laws beyond hyperbolic spaces. AIM Workshop "Random walks beyond hyperbolic groups", San Jose, CA United States
- 2021.12.03. Limit laws for random walks on mapping class groups.  $Conformal\ Dynamics\ and\ Groups\ Seminar,\ BICMR.$  (Online)
- 2021.11.29. Random walks on mapping class groups favor pseudo-Anosovs.  $Dynamics\ Seminar,$   $University\ of\ Toronto.\ (Online)$
- 2021.11.18. Random walks, counting problems and genericity of loxodromics. *Geometry and Topology Seminar, Technion*. (Online)
- 2021.10.06. Random walks on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces. *Tokyo Tech Topology Seminar*. (Online)
- 2021.07.22. Random walks on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces. Pacific  $Dynamics\ Seminar.$  (Online)
- 2021.02.03. Simple length spectra of a generic hyperbolic surface determine its isometry class. Virtual Seminar on Geometry and Topology. (Online)

#### Contributed Talks

- 2022.05.31. Frequently contracting geodesics and random mapping class. *PK2 Topology Workshop*.
- 2022.04.25. Limit laws and their consequences on MCG and Out(Fn). 5-min lightning talk, *IHP Conference "Mapping Class Groups and Out(Fn)"*.
- 2022.01.18. Random mapping classes are pseudo-Anosov. The 17th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2021.01.26. Rigidity of length Identities of hyperbolic surfaces. The 16th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2020.10.30. Random walks and mapping class groups. 10-minute talk at *Geometric Group Theory in East Asia*. (Online)

# Conference organization

- 2023.12.18–20. Hyperbolic Geometry of Numbers, KIAS (with Prof. Sang-hyun Kim, Prof. Ser-Peow Tan)
- 2023.09.27–28. The 1st Korea-Chile Workshop on Dynamical Group Theory, Incheon, Korea. (with Prof. Sang-hyun Kim)

# Teaching

#### At Cornell Instructor, MATH 1110 Calculus I 2024FAt KAIST 2022FTA, MAS102 Calculus II & MAS430 Combinatorial Topology 2022STA, MAS109 Linear algebra and Applications & MAS201 DE and Applications 2021FTA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory TA, MAS109 Linear algebra and Applications & MAS331 Topology 2021S2020FTA, MAS102 Calculus II & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory 2020S Head TA, MAS201 DE and Applications TA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory 2019F2019STA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS331 Topology TA, MAS355 Mathematical Statistics 2018F2017S, 2018S Undergraduate TA, MAS101 Calculus I

## Service & Outreach

- Refereed for Annales Henri Lebesgue, Annales de l'IHP (B), Compositio Mathematica (quick opinion), Israel Journal of Mathematics, Journal of Topology, Mathematical Reviews.
- Published a series of math cartoons on KIAS webzine (Horizon) (in Korean)

# References

Prof. Hyungryul Baik, KAIST
hrbaik@kaist.ac.kr

Prof. Ilya Gekhtman, Technion
ilyagekh@gmail.com

Prof. Sébastien Gouëzel, Université de Rennes 1
sebastien.gouezel@univ-rennes1.fr

Prof. Kasra Rafi, University of Toronto
rafi@math.toronto.edu

Prof. Giulio Tiozzo, University of Toronto
tiozzo@math.utoronto.ca

(Teaching) Prof. Moon-Jin Kang, KAIST
moonjinkang@kaist.ac.kr